Ahmad Alshmali

Consultant Healthcare



Objective

Self commitment & ownership attitude for 10 years of onsite and national level Digital transformation projects with multinationals team work and various type of value optimization focus and client satisfaction.

Self-motivated, team player with strong organizational and interpersonal skills.

Experienced specialist with a passion for delivering outstanding service.



Alshamali988@hotmail.com Saudi Arabia - Riyadh Mar 31, 1988 Jordanian



966542990877 linkedin.com/in/alshamali

Experience

Oct 2019- Present, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Change Management Consultant

GE Healthcare

- Assess level of alignment between current workflows, organizational design and resources with the new system; to identify potential barriers and gaps and determine what processes must be significantly redesigned and support organizational design and definition of roles and responsibilities. Assess the Current State in three key areas: organizational design and workflows staffing and roles Training needs
- Conduct Stakeholders analysis, assess change readiness and develop influencing strategies including the design, development, delivery and management of communications related to the project activities and changes across the Health facility
- Engaged with key leaders and prepare them to lead and control the change
- Handled customer complaints with empathy and composure.
- Recommended new or updated business models. Created business plans, mission statements, and visions.
- Provided medical record information and answered questions and requests from law firms, patients, clinical staff, government agencies, and insurance companies.

May 2015- Aug 2019, Amman, Jordan

Senior Health Analytics

Electronic Health solutions

- Develop and implement effective record-keeping procedures.
- Prepare accurate reports on the latest trends in customer service, billing, and cost evaluation.
- Research and evaluate data from different sources to identify discrepancies and patterns.
- Present and explain status reports to management.
- Recommend ways to improve healthcare quality and minimize costs
- Work with management and other internal departments to implement and assess developments.
- Perform regular site visits to evaluate operations and costs of health care platforms.
- Prepare and organize policy guidelines, public hearing testimonies, presentations, and petitions.
- Planned, developed, operated, and maintained health record indexes and retrieval systems to classify and securely store information.

May 2011- May 2015, Irbid - Jordan

• Healthcare provider - Nursing

King Abdullah university Hospital

- Contributes to care planning, involving clients, and demonstrates an understanding of clients rights to make informed decisions.
- Demonstrates computer skills necessary to organize data for essential care delivery.

- assessing and planning nursing care requirements.
- monitoring and administering medication and intravenous infusions.
- Scheduled weekly rounds to monitor the quality of care on the wards and observe nursing activities

Education

Jun 2012 - Jun 2014, Amman, Jordan

MSc. Health services Management

Royal collage of surgeons in Ireland

- Health Economics
- Management and health information systems
- Financial control in the health service
- Financial management in health services
- Operations management of health services
- Quality management in health services organizations
- Strategic management in the health service organ
- · Leadership & management of change

Jun 2006 - Jun 2010, Amman, Jordan

BSc. Nurse

Jordan University Of Science & Technology

Skills

- Problem-Solving
- communication & Interpersonal skills
- Data analysis and Visualization
- Project management
- Excel and Ms. Project
- Analytical or statistical software

Projects

National Cloud Electronic Medical Record (EMR) Implementation (North Region Hospitals) (23 Hospitals)

National Cloud Electronic Medical Record (EMR) Implementation (South Region Hospitals) (33 Hospitals)

(King Saud Medical City-Riyadh)

National Cloud Electronic Medical Records(EMR) Implementation

Hakeem Project

National Jordanian EHR Implementation

(Government, Military, University Hospitals) (20 Hospitals)

Health data Analytics

Languages

Arabic Native

English Advanced National Jordanian BI Project Value Realization Project Saudi Arabia Partner With Wolters Kluwer

Certifications & Courses

Project Management Professional

Emotional Intelligence In Practice

Art of Management

MOSAIC Leadership Program

Public Relations